[
    {
        "question": "What Canadian province boasts the longest freshwater beach in the world?",
        "answer": "Ontario"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you see the petroglyphs of Newspaper Rock?",
        "answer": "Petrified Forrest National Park"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you visit a museum devoted to failed inventions?",
        "answer": "Austria"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country can you find Piedra del Pe\u00f1ol (also called El Pe\u00f1on de Guatape)?",
        "answer": "Colombia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state shares the shortest border with Canada?",
        "answer": "Pennsylvania"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Welsh name for Wales?",
        "answer": "Cymru"
    },
    {
        "question": "Socotra is an island belonging to what country?",
        "answer": "Yemen"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which sea would you find the Cayman Islands?",
        "answer": "Caribbean Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What strategic body of water does Singapore overlook?",
        "answer": "Straits Of Malacca"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was `Cibik Ridge` in World War II?",
        "answer": "Bougainville Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "An archipelago of 169 Pacific islands known as the `Friendly Islands`, Tonga has what capital city?",
        "answer": "Nuk`alofa"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many 4,000 foot peaks are there in the White Mountains?",
        "answer": "48"
    },
    {
        "question": "What two countries have square flags?",
        "answer": "Switzerland and Vatican City"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Los Angeles` full name?",
        "answer": "El Pueblo de Nuestra Se\u00f1ora la Reina de los \u00c1ngeles de Porci\u00fancula"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest glacier in the world?",
        "answer": "Lambert-Fisher in Antarctica -- It is about 250 miles (ca. 402 km) long and roughly 60 miles (ca. 97 km) wide."
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the term `headwater` mean?",
        "answer": "Source of a stream or river"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s largest meteor crater?",
        "answer": "South Africa -- The Vredefort Crater is the world`s oldest crater and also the world`s largest \u2014 185 miles wide."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s oldest skiing museum?",
        "answer": "Oslo, Norway -- Opened in 1923, Holmenkollen Ski Museum has exhibits detailing 4,000 years of skiing history."
    },
    {
        "question": "What city has the busiest subway system in Europe?",
        "answer": "Moscow -- Opened in 1935, the Greater Moscow Metro has an annual ridership of 2.3 billion people. The system has 239 stations."
    },
    {
        "question": "Badlands National Park is located in which U.S. state?",
        "answer": "South Dakota -- The park has sharply eroded buttes and pinnacles and the largest undisturbed mixed-grass prairie in the U.S."
    },
    {
        "question": "What Mexican political party was voted out of office in 2000, after 71 years in power?",
        "answer": "PRI (Partido Revolucionario Institucional)"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Pindus is the main mountain range in what country?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city was nicknamed `The Paris of the West`?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two US states have shoreline along Chesapeake Bay?",
        "answer": "Maryland and Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which three states share a border with California?",
        "answer": "Arizona, Nevada and Oregon"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are at Chicago`s Comiskey Park, what sport would you be watching?",
        "answer": "Baseball"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Zambia?",
        "answer": "Lusaka"
    },
    {
        "question": "A bouzouki is a stringed instrument from which country?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano `Fuji`?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which Mediterranean Sea are the Cyclades islands?",
        "answer": "The Aegean"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many US states border an ocean?",
        "answer": "23"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which Caribbean island are the Blue Mountains?",
        "answer": "Jamaica"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Mojave Desert city has a name meaning `the meadows` in Spanish?",
        "answer": "Las Vegas"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are you if you land at Norman Manley airport?",
        "answer": "Kingston Jamaica"
    },
    {
        "question": "What takes place in Happy Valley, Hong Kong?",
        "answer": "Horse racing"
    },
    {
        "question": "What continent is Greenland part of?",
        "answer": "North America -- Covering more than 836,000 square miles \u2014 three times the size of Texas \u2014 it is the world`s largest island."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which element gained notoriety from poisoning the waters around Japan?",
        "answer": "Mercury"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Limpopo river?",
        "answer": "Mozambique"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Volta river?",
        "answer": "Ghana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most sacred river of India?",
        "answer": "The Ganges"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a `kartoffel` in Hamburg?",
        "answer": "A potato"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is Lake Como?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the International Court of Justice?",
        "answer": "The Hague"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two Great Lakes does the state of Wisconsin border?",
        "answer": "Lake Michigan and Lake Superior"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the nickname for the island of Trinidad?",
        "answer": "Land of the Hummingbird"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Orient Express train originally ran from Paris to where?",
        "answer": "Istanbul"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do people traditionally dance the flamenco?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "Greenland is part of which kingdom?",
        "answer": "Kingdom of Denmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of Northern Ireland`s one UNESCO World Heritage Site?",
        "answer": "Giant`s Causeway -- It is a dramatic splattering of 40,000 black basalt columns and one of the country`s main tourist attractions."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mutianyu section of the Great Wall of China has the distinction of having what type of designated zone?",
        "answer": "Graffiti -- People are allow to leave messages on a plastic-like screen."
    }
]